hey guys welcome to concept and coding
this is Shan and today in Spring boot we
are going to see how to dynamically
initialize Bean using at theate Value
annotation if you remember in the
dependency injection video I told you
about unsatisfied dependency problem and
how you can resolve it using at theate
qualifier
annotation lot of comments I have
received that hey when we are using at
the rate qualifier notation will it not
break dependency inversion so if you
read all this right all this red lines
you will find one thing that they are
pointing one only one thing that it will
break dependency inversion right so I'll
tell you quickly tell you what is
unsatisfied dependency problem how
qualifier we are using it and then two
solution first and second solution how
we can make it
Dynamic okay so in the unsatisfied
dependency program what what is the
problem is that there is an interface
order and there are two Childs online
order offline order both are at theate
components means manage by
spring so very very basic class itself
one Constructor method and one uh create
order method which is just printing
created online order created offline
orders very
simple now here what happening is we
have a user class which is a
controller now now it has a dependency
on this order object so I have put Auto
order now what would happen is when you
start an application so this controller
is single turn scope because if you by
default is a scope so it is eagerly
initialized so spring will try to create
its object and while creating an object
it will try to resolve the dependency
now a spring doesn't know hey Which
object to assign to this order whether
online order or offline order now spring
doesn't assume anything so it will just
fail application failed to start error
creating Bean with name user it doesn't
able to create the bean user because it
not able to resolve the dependency order
which one online or offline so to solve
this we see that there is one more that
at theate primary and at theate
qualifier so how at theate qualifier was
solving it is we provided the qualif
one name to online order so in the
online order above atate component we
add at theate qualifier give any name
similarly for offline we have added this
annotation at theate qualifier offline
order object any
name and in this user
class in this apart from this what we
were doing before we have also added
this qualifier hey spring when you are
creating an object of user right so
if there are more than one order like
this is just an interface right if there
are multiple Childs you can which one
which object you have to assign to this
one this this qualifier online order
object so this object this class online
order object will get injected
here right so this is where everybody
pointed out that hey Shan when we are
using at theate qualifier it's kind of
we are hardcoded the value
now this order will always be like
online order object if user wanted
offline you can't do it because now when
spring will create a user object it will
only assign this online order so
whenever you will hit an API create
order so order do create order which one
it will invoke online order one created
online order created online order so it
breaks dependency inversion which says
that dynamically you can provide any
value now it's not Dynamic you have
hardcoded it so I'll tell you
that the first solution for the dynamic
using first is using qualifiers itself
so the same order two Childs online
offline the same qualifiers is there for
the online order qualifier is present
for the offline order now here in the
user class what we have done is we have
created two objects
order same one order
object but qualifier is online order
object right so this is the object
online order
object which is of type order and the
qualifier is online order object another
is offline order object again same type
order only and the qualifier is offline
order object okay so see both this
online order and offline order both are
single time both are single turn only
right so both beans will get constructed
so these Bean will get injected here
into this respective objects offline
offline order Bean will get injected
here in this one because of this
qualifier online order Bean will get
injected here in this object because of
this
qualifier right so
now here we have provided two objects
right two
qualifiers two objects now in this
create user now since we want Dynamic
based upon user so now let's say in the
create order I have put okay hey user
what you wanted is online order whether
it's true or false is online order if it
is an online order yes then use online
order object create order use this
one else if it is false it will go to
lse part and use offline order object it
will use this offline
okay so that is clear that how you can
create dynamically using at theate
qualifier and this is very very popular
way this is how actually in live today
industry does it so it's a industry
standard way of doing it so the second
this is kind of a second solution where
you can dynamically uh initialize your
bean so in the second way I have created
an
order you have online order offline
order now notice that there is no add
theate
component there is no at theate
component here too where I am using
configuration Bean that's why I am
manually providing the configuration
now okay so
now rest all the code is same so rest
all code is same no changes only thing
is
I am using now atate bean I have already
explained uh how to create a bean using
at theate Bean
annotation now here see what I have done
is create order Bean so return type is
order so it will create an order type
whether online order or offline order
but I want dynamically so I want I what
I did is used at the rate value
annotation so at theate Value annotation
and this is a placeholder this is how
you do it
okay Boolean is Boolean is online order
and this condition is same if it is
online order return online order object
else return offline order object now you
can ask me hey from where this value
comes see at theate value
means at theate Value is used to inject
values from various sources like
property
file environment variables or inline
literals so in this examples this value
is coming from configuration so in there
is something called application do
properties I have already explained you
in the May one uh May one video right I
think from starting third or fourth in
this playlist so in the application.
properties I have said is online order I
have put
false so now what would happen is this
configuration ultimately get set it to
here right so what spring will does is
so whenever spring will see that okay
atate value is there and whatever the
placeholder is online order now spring
will see okay in the configuration is
same value present if yes it will use
this so the false would be assigned
here so now what would happen is is
online order false it will return
offline order object Okay so whenever
spring has to create a bean of order it
will now use
this okay so now what would happen when
you start an application so in the user
here if you see this is at theate
controller and it's a single turn so
during application startup eagerly
spring triy to initialize this eagerly
so it will create a user
be now it will see that any dependency
yes order it has to to resolve so now
spring tries to resolve or create an
order being which one online or offline
now here if you see no at theate
component is present
so it will see okay is there any
configuration I have been provided yes
there is a configuration provided for
order now it will use this now it will
run this and see that okay at theate
Value any property file something
present yes in property file a table to
find this value
false okay offline order so this will
get inserted
with offline
order okay and when you will hit this
API order. create order will be called
offline order created offline
order and if you want to change
dynamically in the application.
properties itself change it to
true when you change it to true
ultimately this will get changed to
online order because it's like true it
will return online order so see
dynamically we are changing it but here
instead of uh client input we are
changing it based on
configuration and then the first example
we have seen based on the client input
how you can do
it okay so you understand this at the
rate value right it is used to inject
value from various sources like property
file and inline literals inline literals
means you can also provide at theate
Value directly literal a string l you
have provided false true
directly right so this value will get
set to whatever you have set so in this
case
false I hope this should be clear now
how to dynamically initialization of
Bean if there is any doubt let me know
we can discuss further thank you bye